試金石電影公司  望遠鏡娛樂公司  聯合出品
羅傑·伯恩鮑姆 加裏·巴伯  聯合制作
成龍電影工作室  聯合攝制
成龍
歐文·威爾遜
上海正午
劉玉玲
袁羅傑
沃爾頓·高金斯
山德·貝克利
「1881年 中國 紫禁城」
公主駕到!
傑森·康納利  拉斐爾·貝茲
布蘭頓·美林  P·亞德裏安·多佛爾
選角導演：馬修·巴裏  南茜·格裏利·凱斯
服裝設計：約瑟夫·普洛
爹  您把我許配給這樣的人?
不可能的  我不會嫁給他的
既然皇上那麽看重他  就讓皇上嫁給他好了
音樂制作：凱西·納爾遜
公主點頭  青蛙說:
The princess nodded, and the frog said
"你一旦答應  就必須要做到"
"That which you have promised, you must perform."
原創音樂：蘭迪·艾德爾曼
聯合制片人：耐得·陶德  朱爾斯·戴利
非常好  繼續讀
Very good. Keep reading.
編輯：趙汝钜
公主俯身親吻了青蛙
"So the princess leaned in and kissed the frog,
這時  青蛙變成一位英俊的王子
"but as she did, he became a handsome prince
藝術指導：彼得·J·漢普頓
後來他們騎馬到了他的王國
"and they rode off to his kingdom,
從此以後一起幸福地生活
where they lived happily ever after. "
從此以後一起幸福地生活...
Happily ever after.
沒有像"從此以後一起幸福地生活"這樣的事
There's no such thing as " happily ever after."
不會發生在一位真正的公主身上
Not for a real princess.
我這個公主的父親想要我嫁的人永遠是一只青蛙
The prince my father wants me to marry will always be a frog.
攝影指導:丹·門代爾
我的提議仍然有效  我會幫你去美國
My offer still stands. I will help you get to America.
- 美國?  - 那太好了
- America?  - That's very kind.
執行制片人：成龍  陳自強  蘇志鴻
但是我們就要沒時間了
But we're running out of time.
我知道有一艘要駛往美國的船  但是我們必須今晚就走
I know of a ship bound for America, but we must leave tonight.
- 今晚就走?  - 我們得抓緊  公主
- Leave tonight?  - We must hurry, Princess.
制作人：羅傑·伯恩鮑姆  加裏·巴伯  喬納森·格利曼
快點  公主
Hurry, Princess.
編劇：邁爾斯·米勒  阿弗雷德·高奇
公主!
你叫我停?
奴才不敢!
導演：湯姆·戴伊
兩個月以後的今天  中午十二點
你們一定要把十萬根金條啊...
送到內華達州卡森市的教會裏
否則的話  公主性命難保!
萬歲!
奉天承運  皇帝诏曰
特派三位最勇敢的皇家衛兵
陪同皇家翻譯  一同前往亞美利加國保護佩佩公主
- 蒙古漢  - 喳
- Mung Goo Hi.
- 趙超  - 喳
- Zhou Hei.
- 周陸  - 喳
- Chow Lu.
出列
散
接旨
謝主隆恩  萬歲萬歲萬萬歲
姜文  你來幹什麽?
沒有留住公主是我的責任  請允許我一同前往搭救公主
這...不可能
隊長
我老了  只有姜文這麽一個侄子
您就開開恩讓他陪我去一趟吧  啊?
他還能幫著搬搬行李哪
也好
讓那些洋人們教育教育他
是是是
陪我到軍機處報到!
喳
美國  內華達州
美國  內華達州  七周之後
是的  沒錯  就是它
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah, that's it.
好  很好
Okay. Great. Great. Okay.
來這裏  看看這個  在這上面花費了很多時間的
Come here. Look at this. Spent a lot of time on this.
現在  專心點  因爲我不想出任何的差錯
Now, pay attention, 'cause I don't want any mistakes.
我已經計算好了火車的速度  和我們的馬的速度
Now, I've calculated the speed of the train and the speed of our horses.
我們會在這個向量處會合  唯一的變量是風
We meet at this vector. The only variable is the wind.
- 技術上講  如果騎馬到這裏...  - 這是火車?
- Technically, if you travel over here on the horses...  - Is this the train?
那我們就開始即興表演吧  就像我們以前經常做的那樣
All right. We're just gonna wing it... like we always do.
趕上火車  然後再跳上去
Ride down, jump on the train,
把錢搶到手了  回去逛窯子  可以了吧?
hoorah the money, head back to the cathouse, all right?
走吧  快點  開始行動
- Mm- hmm.  - Let's go. Come on. Move out. Go!
你還好嗎?  有點緊張?  新手有點緊張沒關系
You okay? Nervous? It's all right to be nervous when you're new.
你不會有事的  我會照看著你的
You'll be okay. I'll keep an eye on you.
你要做的就是聽我指揮  好了  快點  搶匪們
All you gotta do is follow my lead. All right, look alive, outlaws!
公主俯身親吻了青蛙
"So the princess leaned in and kissed the frog,
這時  青蛙變成一位英俊的王子
"but as she did, he became a handsome prince,
後來他們騎馬到了他的王國
"and they rode off to his kingdom,
從此以後一起幸福地生活
where they lived happily ever after. "
舉起手來  女士們先生們
Reach for the sky, ladies and gentlemen!
- 誰要是...  - 誰要是碰下槍  我就轟掉他的腦袋
Touch that gun and I'll blow your god damn head off!
華萊士你幹什麽?  我可是你們之中唯一可以這樣說話的人
What are you doin'? I sorta like to be the only guy that talks, Wallace.
- 好吧  對不起  - 這就好  沒事
- All right. I'm sorry.  - That's okay. That's okay. Good.
別擔心  走吧  快點  大個  我們走
Don't worry. Come on, come on. Big 'Un, let's go.
爲什麽這個新手在喊話?  你在哪兒找到這個家夥的?
Why is the new guy talking? Where did you get this guy?
你知道我是唯一能喊話的人  好了  大家都保持鎮靜
You know I'm the only one who talks. Okay, everybody keep calm.
你在想要向我開火  對吧?
You think you're gonna shoot me? Is that right?
你在這裏弄到什麽了?  是嗎  你弄到了這把槍?
What you got right in here? Yeah, you got this gun?
你想用這把槍幹點什麽是吧?
You think you're gonna do something with that gun?
快點  淑女  你在紗線裏藏了什麽吧?
Come on, Lady Bird. You got anything in here besides yarn?
都拿出來  都拿出來  都給我拿出來
- You got it out for me!  - Hey!
過來  過來  我們不拿女人的東西
Come here. Come here. We don't steal from women.
走開  靠邊站
Get over here. Take that side.
伸出你的手  伸出你的手
Give me your hand. Give me your hand.
剛才的事真對不起  我道歉
I'm so sorry about that. I apologize.
你第一次看到搶匪?
First time you've seen an outlaw?
害怕?  而且還有點興奮?
Scared? Kind of excited too?
或者都有?  是的
All mixed up? Yeah.
我們上次搶劫火車的時候都是裸體的  當時外面很熱
Last train we robbed, we were naked, it was so hot out.
有某個東西...
Yeah, it was somethin'.
是的  開始時就是這樣的
Yeah, it's got my initials right there.
你在看什麽?
What are you lookin' at?
等等  住手  你在哪兒找到這個家夥的?
Wait! Stop! Where did you get this guy?
- 德克薩斯  - 德克薩斯?  你是精神病嗎?
- Texas.  - Texas? Are you insane?
開槍打我吧  我都不知道  我們在這裏在幹什麽
Just shoot me now, 'cause I don't understand what we're doing here.
先生先生先生先生  過來過來過來  坐下
Sir, sir, sir, sir. Come here, come here, come here. Sit down.
- 對不起  我喝水呀  - 先生  坐下
- Excuse me.  - Sir, sit down.
- 怎麽了?  華萊士  你在幹什麽?  - 我只是在即興表演
- What happened? Wallace, what are you doing?  - I'm just wingin' it.
不  我們不是那樣即興表演的
No! That's not how we wing it!
不要再即興表演了  住手  過來  大個子
No more winging it! Stop! Come on, Big 'Un.
- 你已經沒有即興表演的權利了  - 該死的
- You've lost your "winging it" privileges.  - Damn.
該死的
Damn!
我叔叔呢?
叔叔  叔叔  叔叔你沒事吧  叔叔!
你們誰做的?
誰殺了我的叔叔?  誰幹的?
Who killed my uncle? Who did this?
把炸藥給我  把炸藥給我
Give me the dynamite. Give me the dynamite.
不不不  你留在這裏  你不用跟過來
No, no, no, no. You stay here. You don't get to come.
- 看著華萊士  - 看著這裏
- Keep an eye on Wing Nut.  - Hey, Blue, looky here!
很好
Okay.
- 誰殺了我的叔叔?  - 這是什麽  東方快車嗎?
- Who killed my uncle?  - What the hell is this, the Orient Express?
- 抓住他  - 過來
- Get him!  - Come here!
保險箱就快爆炸了
Wh...Hey! The safe's getting ready to blow!
准備好去拿我們的勞動成果吧
Get ready to reap the fruits of our labor.
抓住他  我們上
Move it! Let's go!
羅伊  你把我們的成果炸飛了
Roy, you just blew the shit out of our fruits.
該死
Oh, shit.
我們得抓到那個中國佬
We got a Chinaman to catch.
站住  站住
Stop! Stop!
站住  別動  轉過來
Stop! Stop! Turn around!
轉過來
Turn around!
到底怎麽...
What the...
- 你是誰?  - 羅伊
- Who are you?  - Hey, Roy!
你不擔心嗎?  我幫你掩護
Don't you worry about a thing! I got you covered!
不
No!
滾下去吧  寶貝  滾下去
Roll, baby, roll!
別動  奧班諾  現在是我說了算
Reach for the sky, O'Bannon! It's my gang now!
我不明白
I don't understand.
你說你的朋友有很多財産的
You said your friend had a large estate.
他是有啊
He does.
- 他到底是幹什麽的?  - 好吧  你可以說他是一個...
- What exactly does he do?  - Well, you could say...
慈善家
he's a philanthropist.
他幫助中國的移民  靠自己的能力生活
He helps Chinese immigrants get back on their feet.
歡迎來到美國  公主
Welcome to America, Princess.
羅方?
Lo Fong.
原諒我沒有行屈膝禮
Forgive me if I do not bow.
卡爾文  這個男人是賣...
Calvin, this man is a trai...
賣國賊
Traitor.
爲什麽?  因爲他從紫禁城逃了出來?
Why? Because he ran away from the Forbidden City?
你的酬金放在桌子上了  安德魯斯先生
Your reward is on the table, Mr. Andrews.
現在你必須加倍付酬金  否則我就殺了她
Well, now you're gonna have to double it, or I'm gonna kill her.
安德魯斯先生  我們中國人...
One thing about the Chinese, Mr. Andrews  ...
我們不會談判兩次的
We do not renegotiate.
如果你覺得我會答應你什麽
Whatever you think I'm going to do for you,
那你就錯了
you're wrong.
簡直是場噩夢
It was just like a nightmare.
你不會相信我所說的
You wouldn't believe it if I told you.
我的同夥把我扔在沙漠裏  我感覺所有的牛仔都恨我入骨
My gang left me in the desert. I felt like all the other cowboys hated my guts.
每個人都是...我只是很想你們  很想你們幾個
Everyone was...I just missed you. I missed all of you.
我們也很想你  羅伊
We missed you too, Roy.
療養時間到了
I think it's medication time.
過來  魔女
Come here, devil woman.
你好調皮
Oh! Ooh, that's naughty.
小心  小心點
Ohh. Ow, careful. Careful with that.
小心...
Ow, ow. Careful. Ow.
該死  禿鹫在啃我的腦袋
Holy crap! The vultures are eating my head!
救命  救命  我的同伴抛棄了我
Help! Help! My gang buried me!
他們把我留下來等死
They left me for dead!
謝天謝地  我還以爲你是幻覺
Oh, thank heavens. I thought you were a mirage.
- 快  水  - 是你
- Oh, come on. Water.  - You.
- 你殺了我的叔叔  - 不
- You killed my uncle!  - Bull!
那都是華萊士幹的
That was Wallace all the way.
- 他是你們這幫強盜中的一個  - 他並不是我們的同夥
- He was one of your bandits.  - He wasn't part of my gang.
他是一個新手  他像馬路上的蜥蜴那麽瘋狂
He was a new guy. He's crazy as a road lizard.
- 你活該等死  - 等等
- You deserve to die.  - Hold on a second.
你知道一件誰都沒提起的事嗎?
You know what no one's saying here?
在火車上我有個機會能殺了你的  但是我卻沒有殺你
I had a chance to kill you on that train, and I chose not to.
因爲我不是個野蠻人
'Cause I'm not a barbarian.
- 你要去哪兒?  - 卡森市
- Hey! Where are you going?  - Carson City.
我挖洞到中國都比你到卡森市還近
I'm closer to diggin' myself to China than you are to gettin' to Carson City.
怎麽走?
- Hey!  - Which way?
這還差不多  把我挖出來我就指給你
Hey, that's better. Dig me out and I'll show you.
怎麽走?
Which way?
你看見那...那座山了嗎?
You see the... mountains over there?
卡森市就在山的那邊
Carson City is on the other side.
好了  把我挖出來  我們的交易就結束了
All right, dig me out. I kept my end of the bargain.
把我挖出來
Dig me out.
自己挖吧
Dig.
- 拜托  - 別說話  慢慢挖吧
- Come on!  - Don't talk. Just dig.
快走  快走啊
快點走  快點走!
我沒告訴過你不能在克勞族的地盤上玩嗎?
對不起  父親
他打敗了六個克勞族人
空手打敗的!
他爲什麽穿著裙子?
卡森市...在...哪裏?
Where is Carson City?
他剛才說的很慢  好像是在尋求幫助
但是我還是不懂他到底在說些什麽
把和睦煙鬥給他  也許能讓他閉嘴
(和睦煙鬥: 印第安人用來表示和睦)
這煙勁可真衝
大家早
女兒
你的丈夫是個 "穿著裙子戰鬥的男人"
不用每天都陪著他
你的職責是看好他
是  父親
不行啊  我跟...
他昨天晚上卻沒有喊過冤
小女兒  把結婚禮物帶來
別煩惱了  他可能不是很合適  不過至少不是白人
我想你可能餓了
I thought you might be hungry.
點心
我不餓
You were wrong.
如果我們能達成某種協議
You would find me a much better host
你會發現我是個更好客的主人
if we could come to some sort of an arrangement.
協議?
An arrangement?
就像你和鐵路上工作的那些奴隸達成的那種?
Like the one you have with the slaves working on this railroad?
到時這些人就可以自由離開了
These people are free to leave.
你想從我這裏得到什麽?
What do you want with me?
一旦得到皇帝的黃金  我的工作就結束了
Once I have the emperor's gold, my work will be complete.
公主
Princess.
現在應該讓你去和你的臣民們在一起了
I think it is time for you to be among your people.
他們看起來不像我看到過的印第安人  傑迪戴亞
They don't look like any injuns I ever seen, Jedediah.
那是因爲他們不是印第安人  他們是猶太人
That's because they're not injuns, woman! They're Jews!
你  留下
You, stay.
夥計們  看看他
You guys, get a load of this.
這兒是卡森市嗎?
Is this Carson City?
不  這兒不是卡森市  酋長
No, this ain't Carson City, Chief.
你得去別的地方打你的烈酒了
You're gonna have to get your firewater somewhere else.
好了  羅伊  下注吧
All right, Roy, ante up.
在外面待著吧
And stay out!
你這麽快就回來了  爬蟲
You bounce back fast, kimosabe.
你在這裏做什麽?  我還以爲你去了卡森市呢
What are you doin' here? I thought you were going to Carson City.
你...你給我指了條壞路
You! You gave me bad directions!
不對  應該說我給你指了條"錯"路
No, I gave you wrong directions.
你想要回你的牙簽嗎?
You want your toothpicks back?
- 你太神經了  來這兒把...  - 把它還給我
- You got a lot of nerve, comin' in here with that...  - Give it back to me!
這是什麽?
Ain't that somethin'?
把你的手拿開
Take your hand off me.
我只是想去卡森市
Hey, I just want to go to Carson City!
送你一程
You're goin' for a ride!
不
No!
好  很好
Yes! Yeah!
好  太好了
Yes! Yes!
不  不
No! No!
對不起  對不起
Sorry! I'm sorry!
你...
You!
- 誰先搗的亂?  - 中國佬
- Who in the hell started this?  - The Chinaman.
把書還給我  放我出去!
把書還給我  放我出去
Let me out! Give me the book back!
我必須去卡森市救公主
I have to go to Carson City to rescue the princess!
你們抓錯人了  我不該被關在這兒
You've got the wrong person! I don't belong here!
讓我出去啊!
繼續說漢語吧  這很有效  他們就要放你出去了
Keep goin' with the Chinese. That's workin'. They're about to let you out.
- 把書還給我  - 他喊得這麽大聲  就把書還給他吧
- Give me the book back!  - For cryin' out loud, just give him the book back, please
- 這樣就能讓我們安靜一會兒  - 把門打開
- If it'll give us some peace and quiet...Forget about it.  - Open it up!
他們不會還你書了  放棄吧
They're not givin' you the book back. Drop the book.
你已經浪費我夠多時間了
I wasted enough time with you
什麽?  我浪費了你很多時間?  關我什麽事啊?
What? You've wasted enough time with me? What about me?
把書還給我
Give me the book!
- 聽我說  別喊了  - 把書還給我
- Listen for a second. Stop!  - Give me the book! Hey!
聽著  別喊了  你不是在東方  明白嗎
Listen! Stop! You're not in the East, okay?
你不是在中國  這是西方
You're not in China. This is the West.
太陽雖然不是在這裏升起來  但它在這裏落下
The sun doesn't rise here, it sets here
你就快讓他們吊死我們了  然後你就能要回那本書了是吧?
and you're closer to getting us hung than you are getting that book back, okay?
現在只是...我喜歡...
Now, just...I like that.
這正是我想說的  你太緊張了
That's what I'm talking about. You're wound so tight.
你是我見過的最暴躁的家夥  放松一下嘛
You're the most irritable guy I've ever been around. Just relax for a second.
這樣十分鍾後你就能出去繼續歇斯底裏了  我保證
Take ten minutes, and then you can go back to screaming, I promise.
到時我會陪你一起瘋的  好了  放松一下
I'll join you. Okay, just relax for a second.
來吧  坐下來
Come on, sit down.
來吧
Come on.
放松一下
Just relax.
你是在放松嗎?
Is that relaxed?
你神情很僵硬
You look sort of rigid there.
你知道嗎?  我們都沒給對方留下好印象
You know what? We got off on the wrong foot.
讓我們試著重新認識吧
Let's try to start again.
夥計  你很能打
Man, you sure can fight.
我從來沒看到過像你這樣的
I've never seen anything like that.
就像...
It was...
我想稱贊你一下
I'm trying to give you a compliment.
你還沒有因爲我給你指錯路而發瘋嗎?
You're not still mad about me pointin' you in the wrong direction, are you?
拜托  你聽到這種笑料應該笑的
Come on. You gotta be able to laugh at stuff like that.
就像我在沙漠中  我毫無怨恨  我只覺得好笑
Like me in the desert. I don't hold any grudges. I laugh about it.
我並不生你的氣  你只留下筷子讓我等死
I'm not angry at you. You just left me there with chopsticks to die.
獨自寂寞  當時只有我和在啃我腦袋的兀鹫
Roy, all by his lonesome. Just me and the buzzards pickin 'at my head.
你是個很沈默的人  對吧?
You're a very silent man, aren't you?
你並不想在那個酒吧中看見我是吧?
You weren't expecting to see old Roy in that bar, were you?
誠實點  是嗎?
Be honest. Were you? Huh?
你真的用筷子逃脫的嗎?
Did you really use those chopsticks?
你最好能相信
You better believe it.
你笑了  這個玩笑很有趣  我要記住它
Now you laugh. That's funny. I gotta remember that one.
好了  你到底是誰?
So, who are you?
我是中國皇帝的皇家衛兵
I'm Imperial Guard to the Emperor of China.
中國
China.
那是什麽書?
What's with the book?
那書是佩佩公主的
The book belongs to Princess Pei Pei
- 誰?  - 佩佩公主
- Who?  - Princess Pei Pei.
她在紫禁城裏被綁架出來
She was kidnapped from the Forbidden City.
紫禁城?  我喜歡紫禁城
Forbidden City? I like that, the Forbidden City.
公主被綁架了  好神秘  繼續說
A princess kidnapped. It's so mysterious. Oh, go ahead.
皇帝派我們接回她
The emperor sent us to get her back.
我們?  你指你火車上的朋友?
Us? You mean your friends from the train?
他們也是皇家衛兵
They are also Imperial Guards.
他們要在四天內將黃金帶到卡森市
They have four days to bring the gold to Carson City
- 什麽黃金?  - 贖回公主的黃金
- What gold?  - The gold for the princess.
那些黃金...黃金是在火車上嗎?
The gold...Was the gold on the train?
是的
Yes.
有多少黃金?
How much gold?
十萬根
One hundred thousand pieces.
先生  先生  可以把那本書給我們嗎?
Sir? Sir? Could you hand us that book, please?
先生  這是個誤會  他...
Sir, there's been a mistake. He has...
先生...對...
Sir...Yeah.
我們要拿回那本書  然後再要把你從這裏弄出去
We're gonna get that book, and we're gonna get you out of here.
- 你幫助我逃脫?  - 是的
- You help me escape?  - Shh. Yes.
- 爲什麽?  - 爲什麽?  我會告訴你爲什麽
- Why?  - Why? I'm gonna tell you why.
因爲在這個世界上有一些事是錯誤的
Because there are some things in this world that are just wrong,
而綁架公主就是其中之一
and stealing a princess is one of them.
是的  那是錯誤的
Yeah. That's wrong.
我再告訴你件事  我很抱歉給你指錯路  讓你翻過那座山
I'll tell you another thing. I feel guilty about leading you up that mountain.
我在胡想什麽啊  在那裏我們浪費了多少時間啊?
What was I thinking? How much time did we waste there?
這太蠢了  也不好笑  對吧?
That was stupid. It wasn't funny. All right?
現在坐好了讓我想想怎麽逃出去
Now, sit tight and let me figure this out.
好了  快點  羅伊
All right, come on, Roy.
也許  也許我假裝不舒服  然後在守衛進來時攻擊他們
Maybe...Maybe I pretend to be sick, then attack the guards when they come in.
你是指囚犯裝病的那種老套?
Okay, you mean the sick prisoner routine?
是嗎  這個在中國還有效嗎?
Yeah. Does that still work in China?
在這裏用可能會死人的
'Cause here it's sorta been done to death.
- 我又有了個主意  - 不不...
- I have another idea.  - No, no, no, no, no.
我告訴你怎麽幫我
Here's how you help me.
你待在那邊  讓我自己在這邊想想
You stay on your side of the room, let me figure it out over here.
好了  你去那邊慢慢玩吧
Okay, you play over there.
思考  思考  這裏有什麽可以用上的  對了
Think. Think. What do we got here? Oh, yeah.
很好
Okay.
有木頭  有一面木頭做成的牆
We got wood. We got a wall made out of wood.
很好  還有枕頭
That's good. Oh, we got pillows.
有枕頭  床單  還有床單和床墊
We got pillows, sheets. We got the sheets and the mattress.
好了  把他們放在一起  好好想想  這些都算上...
Okay, let's put it all together. Let's think. Add it up, add it up.
得出了什麽  得出了什麽
What do we got? What do we got?
你在做什麽?  住手  住手
What are you doing? Stop! Stop!
你到底在做什麽?
- What are you doing?  - Shh.
- 幫我拿著這個  - 不不  這是你的襯衫  自己拿著吧
- Hold this for me.  - No, no. That's your shirt. You hold it.
我喜歡你的幹勁  但我不能和你...
I like your energy, but I'm not with you.
- 襯衫一濕就不容易撕破  - 聽不懂
- When the shirt gets wet, it doesn't break.  - I don't know what that means.
然後...
And then...
好  然後怎麽...然後用濕的襯衫  就能...
Okay. And then what...Then with the wet shirt, you...
扭彎欄杆  這很有效
You bend the bars. That's the pay- off.
別讓我在那種東西上浪費時間了好嗎?
Don't waste my time with stuff like that, okay?
兩千年的文明就只是讓你能想到這些?
A 2,000- year- old civilization, that's all you can come up with?
你真丟臉  你真丟臉
Shame on you. Shame on you.
拜托  停手吧  很丟人的
Come on. Stop, please. It's embarrassing.
- 看  我說行來著  - 沒有  你只說"濕襯衫不容易撕破"
- See? I told you so.  - No, you said, "Wet shirt don't break,"
而不是"尿過的襯衫能扭彎欄杆"
not " Piss shirt bend bar."
- 扭它  - 快幫忙
- Twist it.  - Help.
好  就這樣  就是這樣
Okay, there. Get it. There you go.
就差一點點  對
Just one more. Yeah.
你強壯如牛  來吧  你能做到的
You're as strong as an ox! Go! You can do it!
就是這樣  你做到了  成功了
There, you got it! We're gettin' it!
- 幫我頂著  我先穿過去  - 好
- Hold it for me. I'll get through.  - Okay.
不不不  你頂住它  我先穿過去
No, no, no. You hold it and I'll go through.
不要  別用手  住手
No! Not your hand! Stop.
- 幫我頂著  - 再見了  小雛兒
- Hold it.  - Adios, sucker.
- 什麽?  - 我只是開個玩笑  快點  過來
- What?  - I'm just kidding. Come on. Go.
我不會留下我老朋友的
I wouldn't leave my old pal there.
過來  真的很擠
Go. Really squeeze.
不不...抓著它  抓著它
No, no, no, no. Grab this, grab that.
在這裏繼續你的魔術
Work your magic right here.
- 太幹了  - 什麽?  弄濕它弄濕它  快
- Too dry.  - What? Juice it up. Juice it up. Go.
我做不到  已經沒了
I can't! No more!
該死
Ah, damn it.
快出來  小羅伊  施展你的魔法
Come on out, little Roy. Work your magic.
- 快點  - 我正在努力
- Hurry up.  - I'm trying, I'm trying.
- 別看著我  - 放松
- Stop! Don't look at me.  - Relax!
- 放松  會來的  - 謝謝
- Relax. It'll come.  - Thanks.
- 這很有效  不錯  很好  - 這就叫放松?
- That helps. Yeah. Good.  - Is that called relax?
警長  感謝上帝你在這兒  拿著那把槍
Sheriff! Oh, thank God you're here. Get the guns!
- 拿著我的書  - 我拿到了
- Get my book!  - I got it!
這位漂亮的小姐是誰?
Whoa, whoa. Wow, who's the pretty lady ?
- 那是我的太太  - 你來這個國家多久了?
- That's my wife.  - How long you been in this country?
- 四天  - 幹得漂亮
- Four days.  - Nice work.
你好啊
Hello.
快點  我們走了  搭檔
Come on. Let's adios, partner.
你的運氣真好
Well, best of luck to you.
估計這是你們民族再見的方式
Guess this is what your people call sayonara.
好像菲度給你添了些麻煩
Looks like Fido's giving you some problems there.
你想要我幫忙嗎?
You want me to, uh, give you a hand?
- 不  我自己能做  - 當然  你能
- No, I can do it.  - Sure, you can.
像你這樣個沒有經驗的人怎麽到得了卡森市...
How is a greenhorn like you gonna make it to Carson City...
還要救出公主
and rescue this princess?
停下來  停下來...
Stop, stop, stop, stop.
我受不了了  看我怎麽做吧
I can't take it any more. Watch me do it.
把它這麽弄一下  然後高點的鋪上去
Get it like this and you put it up high.
看見沒有?  騎的時候它會向後滑
See? It'll drift back when you're riding.
- 好吧  我決定做了  - 做什麽?
- All right, I'll do it.  - Do what?
帶你去卡森市  幫你救出皮皮公主
Take you to Carson City, help you rescue Princess " Pee Pee."
是佩佩  公主不用你管
Pei Pei. You do not care about the princess.
你不是非常了解我  是吧?
You don't know me very well, do you?
告訴你一件事
Tell you one thing...
我討厭去想一個無辜的中國貴族在受難
I'd hate to think of an innocent member of Chinese nobility suffering.
我告訴你
Tell you that.
你們那兒的人相信命運是吧?
You people believe in karma over there, right?
我在想我們一再地偶遇一定有個理由
I've been thinking. There must be a reason why we keep running into each other
我以前總是和壞人一起  那種讓我無法信任的人
I've ridden with some terrible men...just people I couldn't trust.
但是當我看著你時
But when I look at you,
你有種特別的東西  而且我能看到
there's something different about you, and I can see it.
我能從你的眼中看見
I can see it in your eyes.
就是印第安人所謂的Chippichawa (注: 娼妓)
It's what the Indians call Chippichawa.
- 那是什麽?  - Chippichawa是貴族
- What's that?  - Chippichawa is nobility.
而且你絕對有這種氣質
And you have it in spades.
你已經給自己找到了個搭檔  這與黃金無關  對吧?
You've got yourself a partner. This has nothing to do with gold, okay?
握手吧
Shake on it.
爲什麽你往手裏吐口水?
Why you spitting in your hand?
這是習俗  爲了達成交易
Well, it's customary, to seal the deal.
快點  我們出發吧
Come on. Let's go.
這會是一次長途旅程
This is gonna be a long journey.
你們從現在起要當心  聽到了嗎?  再見
You boys take care now, you hear? Shalom.
再見
Shalom.
出發
Oh. Let's go.
該死
Yee- haw! Goddamn!
看起來你們在這兒也碰到了倒黴事
Looks like y'all had a twister touch down in here.
- 羅伊·奧班諾和他的搭檔路過城鎮了  - 羅伊·奧班諾?
- Roy O'Bannon and his partner come through town.  - Roy O'Bannon?
羅伊·奧班諾不會再有搭檔了  朋友  他已經死了
Roy O'Bannon ain't got no partner, friend. Roy O'Bannon is dead.
他沒死  他昨晚和那個上海小子逃獄了
He ain't dead. He busted out of jail last night with the Shanghai Kid.
上海小子?  羅伊有了新同夥?
Shanghai Kid? Roy got a new gang goin'?
那個狗娘養的  兩個狗娘養的
That son of a bitch. That two- timin' son of a bitch!
他和那個火車上的中國佬合夥出賣了我們
He double- crossed us with that Chinaman from the damn train!
就是這樣  有點傾斜的角度
Just like that. See, at kind of a rakish angle.
- 不錯  不錯  - 我看起來怎麽樣?
- Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.  - How do I look?
我覺得你看上去很棒  我覺得你就像一個真正的牛仔
I think you look great. I think you look like a real cowboy.
非常利落  紅色的大手帕
Very dapper, red bandana.
羅伊·奧班諾
Roy O'Bannon.
- 我叫姜文  - 約翰·韋恩?
- My name is Chon Wang.  - John Wayne?
姜文
Chon Wang.
- 真是一個糟糕的牛仔名字  - 爲什麽?
- That's a terrible cowboy name.  - Why?
不好  拜托  太糟糕了
No, come on, that's not gonna work. That's horrible.
- 太糟了  這條馬尾辮子也很糟  - 不要
- That's so bad. And so's the ponytail.  - No!
實際上  它看上去也不是很糟糕
It doesn't look that bad, actually.
永遠不要碰我的辮子
Never touch my queue.
那個會殺了我的
That killed! Ow.
- 我們得出發去卡森市了  - 好的
- We have to go to Carson City.  - Okay.
現在  在我們去卡森市之前  我想要教你一些東西  快點
Now, before we go to Carson City, I want to teach you some stuff. Come on.
跟著我做
You just follow me.
- 這是幹什麽?  - 鍛煉敏捷  提高反應力
- What's that?  - Sensitivity. Increased reflexes.
這些是槍  它們可以是你最好的朋友或者最壞的敵人
Now, these are guns. These can be your best friend or worst enemy.
它在我的左手轉了一圈  它在我的右手轉了一圈
That's a spin in my left hand. That's a spin in my right hand.
這是同時旋轉  現在我讓你拿著它
That's two spins. Now, here, I'm gonna let you hang onto this.
看見沒有?  要小心  時刻准備著
See? Whoa. Be careful. Always be ready. Always be ready.
現在  試著深呼氣
Now, try to exhale for long- range shots,
淺吸氣
inhale for short- range.
好了  現在捂住你的耳朵  因爲聲音會很大
All right, now cover up your ears, 'cause this could be loud.
捂住你的耳朵
Cover up your ears.
我像一匹野馬  你無法馴服我
I am like a wild horse. You can't tame me.
雖然你把燕麥放在槽中  我每天都會來吃一點
You put the oats in the pen, though, and I'll come in for a nibble every day.
可一旦你關上那道門  我就會跳過柵欄  讓你永遠看不見我
But if you ever shut that gate, I'll jump the fence. You'll never see me again.
關于你的丈夫...這並不是針對他
Thing about your husband...and this is nothing against him,
因爲我真的喜歡他...
because I really like him...
他來自一個非常男權主義的社會
he comes from a very male- dominated society.
我就這麽說吧
Let me put it this way...
我的馬肯定不是我最好的朋友
my horse is definitely not my best friend.
內華達州  卡森市
現在人們會古怪地看著你
Now, people start looking at you funny,
你只需說  "你好  夥計"
all you gotta say is, " Howdy, partner."
- 你好  夥計?  - 在他們認爲你慢腦筋之前說出來
- Howdy, partner?  - Faster than that or people will think you're slow in the head.
- 你好  夥計  - 你好  夥計
- Howdy, partner.  - Howdy, partner.
- 只需跟著我說  你好  夥計  - 你好  夥計
- Just follow my lead. Howdy, partner.  - Howdy, partner.
- 你好  夥計  - 就在那裏停放好
- Howdy, partner.  - Just park it right there.
不怎麽管用啊
It's not working.
有些人並不像我那麽有耐心  所以今天不是很友好
Some people aren't as tolerant as I am. Not very friendly today.
約翰  你要...
John, what are you...
約翰...
John...
好疼
Ow. Hurt.
還要努力學學的
Okay. We gotta work on that.
行了  約翰  直起來走路
Here you go, John. Straighten up here.
- 羅伊  很疼  - 我知道  約翰
- Roy, it hurts so bad.  - I know, John,
如果你像這樣走路  我可不和你一起走
but I'm not gonna walk with you if you walk like that.
我試試
I'll be okay.
- 羅伊  是你  - 真見鬼
- Hey, Roy. It's you.  - Holy shit!
我成了通緝犯了  你看看
I'm a wanted man. Look at this!
- 五百美金  可真不少  - 讓我看看
- Five hundred bucks! That's a lot of money.  - Let me see.
- 畫的很好  - 小心點  小心點
- Nice picture.  - Careful, careful.
你看看  你知道這意味著什麽嗎?
Wow, look at this. Do you know what this means?
- 這會把少女迷瘋的  - 真的嗎?
- This will drive the girls crazy.  - Really?
沒錯  是真的  快  我們把它們都撕下來
Yes, really. Come on, let's get a couple more of these.
- 不壞嘛  - 我也被通緝了
- It's not bad.  - I'm wanted too!
- 什麽?  - 這個
- What?  - This.
拜托  不對吧
Oh, come on. That's not right.
我知道  我不是從上海來的
I know. I'm not from Shanghai.
不會吧  一個共犯也要一千美金?
No! $1 ,000 for a sidekick?
- 一定是在開玩笑  - 小心點
- You gotta be kidding me.  - Be careful.
司法體制已經完蛋了
Justice system's all screwed up.
一個連騎馬都不會的人竟然還有個很酷的綽號——上海小子
Man can't even ride a horse, and that's a really cool nickname...Shanghai Kid.
這就像是對它的一種...
It's like, got a snap to it that...
麻煩了  約翰  過來  快過來
Uh oh, trouble. John, come here. Get over here.
把他們困在這裏  夥計們
Tie 'em up over here, fellas.
怎麽了?
- What's going on?  - Shh.
你好  夥計
Howdy, partner.
上帝啊  竟然有一隊  他們應該不是在找我們的
Oh, my God, it's a posse. They can't be looking for us.
- 一隊什麽?  - 估計他們只是打這兒路過
- What's " posse"?  - Oh, I think they're passing us by.
他好像是內森·範·克裏夫警長  那個有精神病的殺手
It looked like Marshal Nathan Van Cleef, the psychotic killer.
羅伊·奧班諾  我是內森·範·克裏夫警長
Roy O'Bannon! This is Marshal Nathan Van Cleef.
我知道你們藏在裏面
- Ohh!  - We know you're hidin 'in there.
上帝啊  真的是他  就是他
Oh, God, it is him. It is him.
你最好扔掉你的左輪手槍  舉手出來投降
Why don't you throw down Your six- shooters and come out With your hands up.
還有和你一起的那個人渣
And that goes for the scum you're ridin' with too.
- 他嬴了  - 羅伊  羅伊  沒事的
- He won.  - Roy, Roy, it's okay.
不  這怎麽會沒事  住手  你不了解這個家夥
No, it's not okay! Stop! You don't know this guy!
讓我和他們說說  記著  我們要去救公主的
Let me talk to them. Remember, we have to save the princess.
你要幹什麽?  站...
What are you doin'? St...
- 放輕松  夥計們  - 他們爲什麽開槍打我?
- Go easy, fellas.  - Why are they shooting at me?
就是 "上海小子先生" 這怎麽了?  我是個通緝犯?
What happened to " Mr. Shanghai Kid"? "Oh, I'm a wanted man"?
- 爲什麽?  - 因爲你是個逃犯
- Why?  - 'Cause you're an outlaw.
- 我不是一個逃犯  - 住口  你這個壞人
- I am not an outlaw!  - Stop! You're a bad guy!
- 看看那張海報吧  上面都寫了什麽?  - 把少女迷瘋
- Look at that poster. What does that say?  - Drives girls crazy.
把少女迷瘋?  你是把一隊警察迷瘋了
Drives girls crazy? Drives the posse crazy.
你讓他們想絞死你  吊死你  因爲你是個壞人
Makes them want to hang you, string you up, because you're a bad guy.
- 給你們二十秒時間考慮...  - 上帝啊  給我們一分鍾吧
- You got 20 seconds...  - Aw, God! Give us a minute!
繞到後面去  先生們
Go around back gentlemen.
別讓他耍花招
Make sure he isn't trying to pull the saddle over our eyes
記著  我要活捉那個中國佬
Remember, I want the Chinaman alive.
我不是壞人
I'm not a bad guy.
你是壞人  你和我在一起  你就是一個壞人
You're a bad guy. You're with me, you're a bad guy.
你拉我下水的
Hey, you put me in this situation!
- 我是好人  你是壞人  - 不  我們兩個都是壞人
- I'm the good guy, you're the bad guy!  - No! We're both bad guys!
- 不  只有你是壞人  你去告訴他們  - 不
- No, only you're the bad guy! You go out there and tell them!  - No!
- 我不出去  你自己出去吧  - 不  你必須去
- I'm not going out there! You go out there!  - No, you have to go!
- 我幹的嗎?  - 不錯嘛
- Did I just do that?  - Not bad.
我不會空手道  但是我會"抓狂"  而且我也會用的
I don't know karate, but I know " karazy," and I will use it.
裏面到底怎麽了?
What the hell is going on in there?
你還好嗎?
You okay?
你只是把我從窗戶扔出來而已
You just threw me through a window.
你拿到了那些黃金?
You got that gold?
什麽?  黃金?  什麽黃金?
What? Gold? What gold?
答錯了
Wrong answer.
等等  我...我沒武器  我沒帶武器的
Wait. I'm...I'm unarmed. I'm unarmed!
我沒有槍  等等  我沒有槍  我...
No gun. Hold on, no gun. I don't...
我是沒帶武器  你不能射一個沒帶槍的人
I'm unarmed! You can't shoot an unarmed man.
- 別擔心  我幫你  - 不  約翰  不要  約翰...
- Don't worry. I help you.  - No, John. No, no. John! John...
爲榮譽而戰  你會贏的
Fight with honor. You will win.
你他媽的有精神病啊?  這就是他們在皇家衛兵學校教你的?
Are you frickin' insane? Is that what they teach you in Imperial Guard School?
- 什麽...  - 撿起來
- What...  - Pick 'em up.
這不是上海小子嗎?
If it ain't the Shanghai Kid.
我們來跳個兒童舞怎麽樣?
How about we make the Kid dance?
來吧  你能跳得更好的
Oh, come on! You can do better than that.
你不該搶這趟火車的  孩子
You robbed the wrong train, son.
- 警長  我覺得...  - 閉嘴  把你的槍撿起來
- Look, Marshal, I think that if...  - Just shut up and put on your guns.
這很危險的  你知道嗎?
This is serious, you know?
我們不是爲這個回來的
We don't come back from this.
真是個平庸的想法
That's the general idea.
你在幹什麽?
What the hell you doin'?
別拖延時間了  快點  來吧  孩子
Stop procrastinating. Come on. Hurry up, son.
住嘴  我不會讓你小瞧的  明白嗎?
Stop it! I'm not gonna let you cheapen it. All right?
這是場決鬥  很神聖的
This is a duel. It's a sacred thing.
而且很美  我們和動物的區別就在于此
It's beautiful. It's what separates us from the animals.
我不會怨恨你的  准備好了嗎?
Whew! I do not envy you. You ready?
爲什麽不轉過來像個男人那樣面對我?
Why don't you turn and face me like a man?
爲什麽不按照各自的做法?  怎麽樣?
Why don't you do it your way and I'll do it my way? How about that?
來吧  羅伊  你能做到的
Oh, come on, Roy. You can do it.
不行  你做不到  他會殺了你的
Oh, no, you can't. He's gonna kill you.
- 一...  - 他會把你打飛的
- One.  - He's gonna blow you away.
來吧  羅伊  不要那麽想
Come on, Roy. Don't think like that.
二...
Two.
沒錯  要有信心
Oh, yeah. Be positive.
想象自己是子彈  是彈頭
Be the bullet. Be the lead bullet.
- 我要死了  - 三...
- I'm about to die.  - Three.
羅伊
Roy!
決鬥取消
Duel's off!
羅伊
Roy!
你壞事了  約翰
You blew it, John!
不能妨礙一個正在決鬥中的人
Never interrupt a man in the middle of a duel.
我可以搞定他  你差點害死我  我就要搞定他了
I had him. That's what kills me. I had him! I had him!
大家小心啊!
現在你知道給你擡轎的人的感受了吧
Now you know how it feels to haul you around in that sedan chair.
我絕不會向你低頭的
I will never bow to you.
好好看看這些臉
Take a good look at these faces.
如果你企圖逃跑
If you attempt to escape,
我會每小時殺一個工人...
I will kill one worker every hour...
直到找到你爲止
until you are found.
從她開始殺
Starting with this one.
別讓他看見你受苦
Do not let him see you suffer.
我知道你是誰
I know who you are.
請別告訴任何人
Please, tell no one.
你稱這是個特別的藏身之處?
You call this a special hideout?
是的  它是  約翰
Yes, it is, John.
它還是個收集情報的好地方
It's also a good place to gather intelligence,
因爲每個經過卡森市的人都逃不過這些人的耳目
'cause no one passes through Carson City without these people hearing about it.
- 你會向他們詢問公主的下落嗎?  - 是的  先生  我會的
- Would you ask them about the princess  - Yes, sir, I will.
而且我不管這會有多丟臉
And I don't care how ugly it gets.
不問過每一個人我決不休息  可以了吧?
I'm not gonna rest until I've pumped everybody in there for information, okay?
- 你好  羅伊  - 你們好啊  女士們
- Hi, Roy.  - Roy.  - Hello, ladies.
給這對亡命之徒讓讓路吧
Make way for a couple of desperados.
很高興再次見到你  羅伊先生
Nice to see you again, Mr. O'Bannon.
- 你好  - 羅伊
- Greetings. Hello.  - Roy.
沒錯  我們在這裏會找到些情報的  相信我
Oh, yeah, we're gonna get some information here. Trust me.
這不是個藏身的好地方
This is not a proper hiding place.
拜托  約翰  讓我們放松一下
Oh, come on, John. Let's relax for a little bit.
- 來喝一杯  - 不  我要去找公主
- Here, have a drink.  - No. I wanna find the princess.
我也要去  但是我們沒法在卡森市挨家挨戶的找她
So do I, but we can't exactly go door to door in Carson City looking for her.
- 不要忘了  我們正被通緝呢  - 都是你害的
- Don't forget, we're wanted men.  - Only because of you.
對對對  每件事都是我的錯
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Everything's my fault.
公主是個什麽樣的人?
So, what's the princess like?
約翰  公主長得怎麽樣?  她很漂亮嗎?
John, what's the princess like? Is she pretty?
- 還是非常討厭?  - 你不能議論她
- Is she a pain in the neck?  - You are not fit to talk about her.
約翰  你最好記得你在哪裏
John, you better remember where you are.
這是西方  不是東方
This is the West. It's not the East.
- 記住了嗎?  - 但是太陽還是在東方升起...
- Remember?  - And the sun may rise where I come from...
行了行了  你這些廢話我知道了
Blah, blah, blah. I know.
很好  你還記得
Good. You remember.
- 她是單身嗎?  她還是單身嗎?  - 什麽?
- Is she single? Is she single?  - What?
她已婚了嗎?  我可以娶她嗎?
Is she married? Is she available?
只有皇室成員可以
Only to a member of the Imperial family.
你是一位皇室成員嗎?  我看不像
Are you a member of the Imperial family? I don't think so.
那是個笑話嗎  約翰?  那是個笑話
Was that a joke, John? That was a joke.
約翰  那是你的第一個笑話
John, that was your first joke.
我們來幹一杯  爲你的第一個笑話
We gotta have a toast. Your first joke.
- 沒錯  沒錯  - 不是
- Yes. Yes.  - No.
快點  喝一杯
Come on. Drink.
- 就一杯  - 行
- Just one.  - Okay.
但是不要再議論公主了
But don't talk about the princess any more.
以名譽擔保
Word of honor.
行酒令很有意思的
Be fun to play a drinking game.
- 你會中國的酒令吧?  - 不會
- You know any Chinese drinking games?  - No.
每個國家有酒令的  你肯定也知道一個
Every country has a drinking game. You must know one.
就一個?
Just one?
螃蟹一  腳八個  兩頭兒尖尖這麽大的個兒
眼一擠呀, 脖一縮, 爬呀爬呀過沙河
兩個好啊該誰喝, 三個三個該誰喝,
五個五個該誰喝, 兩個兩個該你喝!
- Uno mas  - Uno...什麽?
- Uno mas?  - Uno...What?
- 再來  Uno mas  - 好
- One more. Uno mas.  - Okay.
螃蟹一, 腳八個, 兩頭兒尖尖這麽大的個兒
眼一擠呀  脖一縮  爬呀爬呀過沙河...
不  我輸了?  再來
No! I lost? One more.
我好迷惘  約翰
I'm so lost, John.
百分之九十的時間我甚至不知道自己在西部這裏幹什麽
Ninety percent of the time, I don't even know what I'm doin' out here in the West.
糟糕的亡命徒
Terrible outlaw.
- 不  你是一個優秀的亡命徒  - 拜托  我總是把事情搞砸了
- No, you're a good outlaw.  - Stop, please. I'm a screw up.
- 不  我才是呢  看看我這些傷疤  - 不對
- No, I am screw up. Look at my scar.  - No.
一個是因爲執勤時遲到了
One for arriving late At a guard duty.
還有一個是因爲掉了軍棍  你算不錯了  我看見過你這樣
One for dropping fighting stick. You good. I saw you.
我唯一擅長的事就是胡吹神侃
The only thing I'm good at is talking.
- 是真的  - 約翰
- It's true.  - John.
拿開你的手  約翰
- Huh?  - Take your hand off me, John.
再來玩會兒?
One more game?
不  不喝了  就這樣了
No. No more drinking. That's it.
- Uno mas?  - 不玩了  約翰  不玩了
- Uno mas?  - No mas, John. No mas.
羅伊?
Roy?
- 你能過來嗎?  - 菲菲?
- Are you coming?  - Fifi?
你那個看起來很搞笑的朋友是誰?
So, who's your funny- looking friend?
我不知道
I don't know.
他是個我碰到的瘋狂的皇家衛兵
He's this crazy Imperial Guard I met.
他...他真的很搞笑
He's- He's really funny.
這家夥歇斯底裏的
- Ё  - The guy's hysterical.
我們正在玩遊戲  你看見了嗎?  我們只是在玩那個酒令
We were just playing...Did you see us? We were just playing that game.
姜文開始...
John's going...
接著我就這樣...雖然不明白他說的是什麽  但是...
And I was going...You can't really understand what he's saying, but...
羅伊  羅伊  我沒想到你和一個中國佬混在一起
Roy? Roy? I never figured you for riding with a Chinaman.
其實我並不是真正地和他一起闖蕩  菲菲
Well, I'm not exactly riding with him, Fifi .
他不是我的朋友  你知道的  我是說  他是個中國佬
He's not my friend, you know. I mean, he's a Chinaman.
好的  很好
Well, that's good.
我是說...你們真的...
I mean...And you really...
你們這些人在議論他是什麽人?
Were you guys talking about who he was?
我們來談點別的東西吧
Let's talk about something else.
你看起來很迷人  不是嗎?
Don't you look delicious?
- 發生了什麽事?  - 很好
- What's going on?  - Well.
- 是你  - 這不是上海小子嗎
- You!  - If it isn't the Shanghai Kid.
給你
Here.
謝謝你
Thank you.
謝謝
Ahh. Thank you.
約翰  快點  我們得走了
John, come on. We gotta get going.
- 警長在樓下  - 不對不對  警長在那兒呢
- The marshal's downstairs.  - No, no, Marshal's in there.
約翰  你對他做了什麽?
Oh, man, John. What'd you do to him?
- 快點  我們走  - 不
- Come on. Let's get going.  - No!
- 我不和你一起走  - 快點  約翰  該死  你喝醉了
- I don't wanna ride with you.  - Come on, John. Damn, you're a mean drunk.
- 馬兒  - 好吧
- Hi, horsey!  - All right. Shh, shh, shh.
- 現在是"呀呼"的時間  - 呀...什麽?
- All right, it's time for a "yee- haw."  - Yee- what?
羅伊專用
Shh, shh, shh. Roy O'Bannon special.
我們跳下去  騎在馬背面上  大喊"呀呼"
We jump off, land on the back of the horse, yell "yee- haw..."
然後就騎馬離開  怎麽樣?
and ride off, all right?
看著我做  然後跟著做  呀呼
Watch me and do exactly as I do it. Yee- haw!
- 馬頭在哪兒?  - 約翰
- Hyah! Where's the head?  - John!
約翰  起來
John, get up !
抓住他們
Tie 'em up.
我的馬怎麽了?  它死了嗎?
What happened to my horse? Is he dead?
沒有  但是我們快死了  約翰
No, but we are, John.
- 馬兒  你睡著了嗎?  - 起來
- Hi, horsey. You sleeping?  - Get up.
你們的裝備讓人很吃驚嘛
Mighty impressive hardware you're packin'.
把你的視線從我的東西上挪開  你這婊子養的
Why don't you get your eyes off my package, you twisted son of a bitch.
- 我希望他該走了  - 輪到你了
- I hope that's him leaving.  - Your turn.
謝謝你  範·克裏夫先生
Thank you, Mr. Van Cleef.
好了好了  這裏都是什麽人呢?
Well, well. What have we here?
我猜是奧班諾先生
Mr. O'Bannon, I presume.
我能喝杯水嗎?  我口幹...
Can I get a drink of water? I got cotton mouth. Aah!
別再提了
Don't mention it.
這肯定是出名的上海小子
And this must be the famous Shanghai Kid.
- 姜文  - 羅方?
- Chon Wang?  - Lo Fong?
你還記得你的老戰友呢
You remember your old comrade- in- arms?
我記得一個賣國賊
- Hmm?  - I remember a traitor.
我感到一股仇恨
I'm sensing some bad blood here.
黃金在哪兒?
Where is the gold?
佩佩公主在哪兒?
Where's Princess Pei Pei?
住手  拜托  我們是人  我們不是Pinata
Stop. Come on. We're men. We're not pinatas.
(Pinata: 墨西哥小孩過生日時蒙眼亂打的容器)
好嗎?  而且我們在被威脅  我們也不想做硬漢
Okay? And we're really hung over. We 're not trying to be tough guys.
你想談論黃金  我們就談論黃金
You wanna talk about the gold, let's talk about the gold.
那麽是你拿到了我的黃金?
So, you have my gold?
- 你的黃金?  - 是的  黃金在我們手裏
- Your gold?  - Yes, we have the gold.
- 在哪兒?  - 黃金在一個安全的地方
- Then where is it?  - The gold's in a safe place.
他說的是真的嗎?
Is he telling the truth?
不是
No.
很好  約翰  幹得漂亮  那就用你的腳想個辦法
Ow ! Nice, John. Way to go. Way to think on your feet.
他不能撒謊的  他被皇家法律約束著
He cannot lie. He is bound by Imperial decree.
皇家法律
Imperial decree.
爲什麽你不能多認識一下你現在並不是在中國...
When are you gonna learn you're not in China any more?
他不會"學習"  他只懂服從命令
He will never learn. He can only follow orders.
至少我還有我的尊嚴
At least I still have my honor.
奴隸是沒有尊嚴的
Slaves have no honor.
不  不
- No! No!  - Hey!
現在你永遠都回不了中國了
Now you can never go back to China.
你搞砸了  你搞砸了  夥計
You blew it. Whoo! You blew it, man.
相信我  你不該剪掉他的頭發的
You do not want to cut his hair off, trust me.
不要怪我  孩子
Nothing personal, boys.
永遠對皇帝效忠
My loyalty is to the emperor.
沒錯  約翰  我聽到的都是關于皇帝的
Yeah, John, I heard all about the emperor.
肯定是個不怎麽樣的人
Must be a hell of a man.
他只有十二歲
He's only 1 2.
你在玩我嗎?  你站在這兒讓繩子套住你的脖子等死
Are you kidding me? You're sitting here with a noose around your neck...
就是爲了一個蛋蛋還沒長出來的人效命?
ready to die for someone whose balls haven't even dropped?
根據內華達州的法律賦予我的權利
By virtue of the authority vested in me through the territory of Nevada,
我宣布對這兩個人實行絞刑
I do hereby order these men to hang by their necks...
直到他們停止掙紮
until their feet quit kicking.
你們馬上就要下地獄了  孩子們
You're goin' to hell, boys,
你們的馬會帶你們去
and your horses are taking you there.
勒死他們
Tighten 'em up.
吊死他們  吊死他們
Hang 'em! Hang 'em!
小心點  你這小混蛋
Hey! Watch it, you little punk.
吊死他們  吊死他們
Hang 'em! Hang 'em! Hang 'em! Hang 'em!
約翰  你在幹什麽?
John, what are you doing?
發生了什麽事?  停住那些馬
What the hell is goin' on here? Stop those horses!
停住它們
Stop them!
快拉  快拉
Pull it! Pull it!
救命
Help me
別只是站在那兒  去追他們
Well, don't just stand there! Go after them!
聽到小溪的水流聲了嗎  約翰?
Will you listen to this creek, John?
我從沒發現這個聲音這麽美
I've never noticed what a beautiful melody a creek makes.
從來沒有
I've never taken the damn time.
看著這些山和這些樹
Look at these mountains and these trees.
見鬼  看看這些綠樹  過來  我甚至不知道名字...
Hell, look at these green trees. Come here. I don't even know the names...
我們要了解下這些綠樹的名字  過來
We're gonna learn the names of these green trees. Come here.
我想要你看看
I want you to look at these.
我們就不能...約翰  你在做什麽?
Can we not...John, what are you doing?
你還在心疼你的頭發?
Are you still worried about your hair?
約翰  聽我說  你太愛虛榮了
John, listen to me. You're very vain.
等你七十歲的時候  你的馬尾辮...
By the time you're 70, your queue, your ponytail...
會煥然一新
will be as good as new.
- 你在幹什麽?  - 我要離開
- What are you doing?  - I'm leaving.
我們就不能休息幾秒鍾  約翰?  我們剛剛幸免一死
Can we not take two seconds, John? We just cheated death.
快點  花點時間看看這些山
Come on. Let's look at these mountains for a second.
- 好吧  我去拿東西  天哪  你真讓人難以置信  - 我自己走
- Okay, let me get my stuff. God, you're unbelievable.  - I'm going alone.
你要怎...約翰  你說什麽?
What are you...John, what are you talking about?
- 我聽到了  - 你聽到什麽了?
- I heard you.  - You heard me. Okay.
在金發女郎的房間
At Goldie's.
你說我不是你的朋友
You said I wasn't your friend.
約翰...
John...
等一下  約翰  我當時是和一個女人說的
Hold on a second, John. I was talking to a girl.
- 那是...你沒聽到來龍去脈...  - 羅伊
- It was...That's taken out of context. That's not...  - Roy.
你是對的  我怎麽可能是你的朋友
You were right. How could I ever be your friend?
我只是個中國佬
I'm just a Chinaman.
等等  約翰  對不起  我不是那個意思...
Hold on, John. I'm sorry. I didn't mean it to...
再見  羅伊
Sayonara, Roy.
大家小心啊
在這裏等一下
Wait here.
請進
Please.
你走了段很長的路
You have come a long way.
我希望你尋找的公主值得你這麽奉獻
I hope the princess you seek is worthy of such devotion.
把她帶回去是我的職責
It is my duty to bring her home.
我甚至帶了她的最喜歡的書
I even brought her favorite book.
你真是太好了
That's very kind of you.
但是如果你發現公主不願意回紫禁城
But what if you found the princess and she did not wish to go back
那怎麽辦?
to the Forbidden City?
她爲什麽想要留在這裏?
Why would she want to stay here?
也許她在這裏比她回到中國...
Maybe she can do more for the people here...
能爲她的人民做更多的事
than she could back in China.
佩佩公主
Princess Pei Pei.
請不要引起注意
Please, don't draw attention.
請站起來
Please. Stand up!
公主  你必須跟我走
Princess, you have to come with me.
不行  不能讓羅方發現我走了
I cannot. Fong cannot find me missing.
公主  我不能把你留在這裏
Princess, I cannot leave you here.
請站起來
Please, standup!
不要下跪  起來
Don't bow! Get up!
起來
Get up!
你必須走了
You must go.
如果我走了  羅方會亂殺無辜的
If I leave, Fong will begin to kill the others.
把你帶回去是我的職責
It is my duty to bring you home.
我命令你快走
I command you to go.
走
Go!
舉起手來  禿驢
Reach for the sky, baldy!
沒錯  羅伊來了
That's right. It's Roy.
我打擾你們了嗎?
Am I interrupting?
我一直跟著你  怎麽了?
I followed you. So what?
你想讓我怎麽樣  讓你漂泊?  你是一個生手啊
What am I supposed to do, let you wander off? You're a greenhorn.
你會死在這裏的
You'll get killed out here.
快點  我們必須離開這裏  搭檔  快點
Come on! We gotta adios out of here, partner! Come on!
你終于跟我走了
Hyah! You gotta stick with me.
別忘了  "我們"還要去解救公主
Don't forget, we got a princess to save.
公主!
把刀放下
把金子拿過來
公主
代我向皇帝問好  公主
Give my regards to the emperor, Princess.
- 姜文?  - 姜文?
- Chon Wang?  - Chon Wang?  - Chon Wang?
沒錯  "約翰·韋恩"在這兒
That's right, Johnny Wayne is here.
是我
Hey, it's me.
你爲什麽剪了他的頭發?
Why did you cut his hair?
我警告過你  但是你不聽
I tried to warn you, But you wouldn't listen.
快  放下槍
Go on, drop the gun.
現在  踢給我
Now, slide it over.
是她嗎?
Is that her?
她很漂亮
She's pretty.
把握住喽
Grab her.
快點  我們離開這裏  夥計們
Come on. We'll take it from here, guys.
我不會讓你把公主帶回去的
你以爲你是誰啊
你忘了你的任務了?!
而且公主也不願意回去
聖旨下, 姜文接旨
約翰  幹什麽...約翰  起來
John, what...John, get up.
你在幹什麽...我想我們可以省略這些了吧
What are you...I thought we were past this.
快點  約翰
Come on, John.
奉天承運...
皇帝诏曰: 特派三位最勇敢的...
看見沒有?  他永遠都是個奴隸
Do you see? He will always be a slave.
...皇家衛兵  陪同皇家翻譯  一同前往...
...亞美利加國保衛佩佩...
這是西方
This is the West,
不是東方
not the East.
而且太陽也許是從我們那裏升起
And the sun may rise where we come from
但是它在這裏落下
but here is where it sets.
你用我翻譯嗎?  公主留下來了
You want me to translate? The princess stays.
公主留下來了
The princess stays.
我要黃金了  你就和公主結婚吧
I grab the gold, You marry the princess.
我們倆搞定羅方  打完收工  任務就完成了
We both hang Fong and call it a day. Mission accomplished.
好了好了
Well, well.
很高興發現大家都是經常做禮拜的人
Nice to see we're all churchgoers.
婊子養的  他拿著我的槍
Son of a bitch! With my own guns!
很親切  對吧?
Sweet, ain't it?
怎麽樣  這個僵局?
How about that? It's a Mexican standoff.
只有我們不會
Only we ain't got no Mexicans.
公主!
不
No!
公主  小心
Princess Pei Pei!
- 保護公主  - 好
快走啊!
- 公主, 快走啊!  - 不走!
- 我打到你了嗎?  - 沒有
- I hit you?  - No.
但是你真的只差一點點
But you're gettin' really close.
你差點殺了我  差不多已經有十七次了
You've almost killed me, like, 17 times already.
十八  十九  二十
Eighteen, nineteen, twenty!
你今天火氣真大
You're on fire today!
公主  你快去救公主
姜文  接著
你怎麽逃出這裏呢?
How do you survive out here?
什麽意思?  這些不是我的...這些槍真的很難用
What's that supposed to mean? These aren't my...These guns are really weird.
不要啊
Oh, man.
上來
快點走
Stay low!
公主  過來
抓住  公主
也許過去的事就該讓它過去吧  你射的幾槍都很准
Maybe we should let bygones be bygones. You got off some good shots.
我也有幾槍射的不錯  我們打了個平手
I got off some good ones. Let's call it a tie.
怎麽了  奧班諾?  沒子彈了?
What's the matter, O'Bannon? Out of bullets?
不是  還有一發
No, I got one left.
告訴你我接下來要怎麽做吧
Tell you what I'll do.
我取出所有的子彈  只留一發
I'll take out all my bullets but one.
這樣我們就平等了  怎麽樣?
And that way, we'll be even. How's that?
好  聽起來很公平
Okay. That sounds fair.
你肯爲我那麽做嗎?
You'd do that for me?
會啊
Oh, yeah.
當然會了
You bet I would.
我們數三下後出來
We come out on three.
我知道  但是...得讓我來數
I know, but- but let me count.
爲榮譽而戰  很好
Fight with honor. Okay.
爲榮譽而戰...好了  一...
Fight with...Okay. One!
二  二點五...
Two! Two and a half!
二點七八...
Two and seven- eights!
三
Three!
怎麽可能會這樣?
How the hell did that happen?
真是個奇迹
It's a miracle.
我是無敵的
I am invincible.
羅伊
Roy!
無敵的
Invincible!
- 現在你的死期到了  - 再見  搭檔
- Now it's time for you to die.  - Adios, partner.
- 他沒事吧?  - 沒事
羅伊
Roy!
他拿走了黃金
He took the gold.
你關心的只有黃金嗎?
Is that all you care about is the gold?
你真丟臉
Shame on you.
人生裏有很多東西比錢更重要  我希望有一天你能了解
There's more to life than money. I hope you learn that one day.
發生了什麽事?
What happened?
什麽?  沒什麽沒什麽  我只是殺了他而已  你怎麽樣?
What? Nothing, nothing. I just killed him. How'd you do?
怎麽做到的?
How?
你什麽意思  "怎麽做到的"?  我是用自己的槍打死他的
What do you mean, how? I shot him with my gun.
拜托  告訴我真相
Come on. Tell me the truth.
讓人難以置信  你錯過了一個奇迹  我當時只剩下一發子彈
It was unbelievable. You missed a miracle. I had one bullet left.
他卻有無數發  他騙我說他也只有一發了
He had, like, a million left. He lied to me and told me that he only had one too.
但是...但是這時...但是當他...
But-But when...But when he...
將在外, 軍令有所不受
- 她留下來了?  - 是的
- She's staying?  - Yes.
- 我能站起來嗎?  - 可以
- Can I stand?  - Yes.
舉手投降吧  奧班諾
Reach for the sky, O'Bannon!
那是我的台詞  他偷了我的團夥  他還要偷我的台詞
That's my line. He stole my gang, he's stealing my lines.
- 真是難以置信  - 羅伊  羅伊
- That's unbelievable.  - Roy! Roy!
回來
Get back!
住手  住手  是華萊士
Stop, stop. It's Wallace.
羅伊
Hey, Roy
我們知道你和火車上的那個黃種人一起暗算我們
we know you been moonlightin' on us with that old yellow fella from the train!
你們留在這裏  這不是你們的戰鬥
You guys, you stay here. This isn't your battle.
不  我們一起去  我們是搭檔
No, we stick together. We are partners.
太好了
That's beautiful.
你從後門出去
You go out the back door.
- 不  - 不要擔心  公主
- No.  - Don't worry, Princess.
我答應你  我們會再見的
I promise you, I will see you again.
你一旦答應...
That which you have promised...
就必須要做到
you must perform.
小心保護公主
姜文
- 讓開  - 爲什麽?
- Get out of the way!  - Why?
- 快點!  - 爲什麽?  你要幹什...
- Come on!  - Why? What are you...
- 你在幹什麽?  你瘋了嗎?  - 不  約翰  住手  住手
- What are you doing? Are you crazy?  - No, John, stop, stop.
他們打不到我的  冥冥中會發生一些事  是奇迹
They can't touch me. Something happened back there. It was a miracle.
- 不會...  - 笨驢  聽到了沒?
- There's no way...  - Hey, smart-ass! Do you hear me?
時間到了  奧班諾  台詞彩排結束了
Time's up, O'Bannon! It's the end of the line!
我們能搞定這些家夥的  是的  我們能搞定的
We can take these guys. Yep, we can take them.
你出不出來?
Are you comin' out or ain't you?
槍
Gun.
你真是"上海小子"啊
You really are the Shanghai Kid.
很高興與你合作  搭檔
Nice riding with you, partner.
我們數三下就出去  我來數
We go out on three. I count.
不  我來數
No, I count.
我們兩個一起數
We'll both count.
一  二  三
One, two, three!
- 印第安人  小心  - 不  我的家人  我的家人
- Indians! Look out!  - No! My family! My family!
- 朋友們  兄弟們  - 羅伊
- Friends. Brothers!  - Roy!
我告訴你  我們一直當你是笨蛋  但是...
I gotta tell ya, we always figured you for a dumb shit, but, uh,
我們想也許你想回來重新入夥
we was thinkin' maybe you wanna come back and rejoin the gang.
- 所以  你會回來嗎?  - 是的  你會回來嗎?
- So, uh, what do you  say?  - Yeah, what do you say?
我想我只會參加"即興表演"
I think I'm just gonna wing it.
好吧
All right.
- 而你們要進監獄  - 那也行
- And you are goin ' to jail.  - That works too.
好  爬蟲
How, kimosabe!
站在你旁邊真是太好了
Oh, it's nice to be standing here next to you.
我還以爲我沒有機會謝謝你...
I don't think I've ever gotten a chance to Thank you for...
多次搭救我們
for saving us so many times.
我希望你能了解...我感覺好像我們之間有些隔閡
I wish you could understand what...I feel like there's this gap between us.
比如  我是一個牛仔  你卻是一個印第安人
It's like, I'm a cowboy, you're an Indian.
你說"貝殼串珠"  我說"錢" (印第安人用作貨幣或飾品)
You say "wampum," I say " money."
在某些方面  我只是想...
At a certain point, I just think...
閉嘴  羅伊  你廢話太多了
Shut up, Roy. You talk too much.
她...她...她剛才...
Did...Did...She just...
她就在那兒  很准時  帶著很大的賬本
There she is, right on time, carrying a big, fat payroll.
我不知道我是不是會習慣這個
I don't know if I'll ever get used to this one.
不要擔心  你會習慣它的
Don't worry. You'll get used to it.
我向你保證  我們不會讓超過一半的女人成爲執法人士的
I can guarantee you, we won't get half as many girls being lawmen.
我知道人們都想要什麽  但是...
I know we're spoken for, but...
你永遠不會知道在某種關系中會發生什麽
You never know what's gonna happen in a relationship.
我要去掉我那個亡命徒的名字  我不會再用它了
I gotta get rid of my outlaw name. That's not gonna work any more.
真的?  你會叫自己什麽?
Really? What would you call yourself?
我不知道  我想我真正名字是懷亞特·厄普  但是...
I don't know. I mean, my real name's Wyatt Earp, but...
厄普?  真是一個糟糕的牛仔名字
Earp? That's a terrible name for a cowboy.
- 爲什麽?  - 爛
- Why?  - Bad.
- 真的嗎?  - 爛
- Really?  - Bad!
- 那約翰·韋恩是個偉大的牛仔名字?  - 羅伊  看
- And John Wayne's a great cowboy name?  - Roy, look.
他們在那裏
There they are.
是的  看看那些業余選手  那是我的
Yep. Look at those amateurs. That's my move!
快點  羅伊  我們去說"你好"
Come on, Roy. Let's go say " howdy."